Guide to the UNITE HERE Records, 1913-2010
UNITE HERE Records
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
UNITE HERE Records, 1913-2010
6200
UNITE HERE (Organization)
77.5 linear feet
Audiovisual material, awards, banners, correspondence, memorabilia, photographs, publications, records, scrapbooks.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Records of UNITE HERE, especially Local 23-25, and its predessor unions, UNITE and HERE.
UNITE HERE ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
UNITE HERE is a labor union in the United States and Canada, that was formed in 2004 by the merger of the Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees (UNITE) and Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE). The membership is made up mainly of workers in the hotel, food service, laundry, warehouse, and casino gaming industries. In 2005, UNITE HERE left the AFL-CIO and joined the Change to Win Federation along with other unions including the Teamsters, SEIU and the UFCW. In May 2009, Bruce Raynor, president, left UNITE HERE, taking with him several local unions and between 105,000 and 150,000 members. They formed Workers United.
September 17, 2009, UNITE HERE announced that it would re-join the AFL-CIO.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Raynor, Burce; Hotel Employees & Restaurant Employees International Union; HERE (Organization); UNITE HERE (Organization); UNITE (Organization); Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; New School University; Sidney Hillman Foundation; Textile Workers Union of America; Workers United
Subjects:
Clothing workers--Labor unions--United States; Collective bargaining--Clothing industry--United States.; Collective bargaining--Textile industry--United States.; Textile workers--Labor unions--United States.
Form and Genre Terms:
Audiovisual material.; Awards.; Banners.; Correspondence.; Memorabilia.; Photographs.; Publications.; Records.; Scrapbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
RELATED MATERIALS
6000: UNITE Records.
6199: HERE Records.
6284: Workers United Records.
CONTAINER LIST
- 6200 AV: UNITE HERE Audio-Visual Materials, 2001-2004., Contains VHS tapes of the merger convention for UNITE and HERE, as well as other VHS tapes and CD/DVDs.
- 6200 MB: UNITE HERE New York Joint Board Memorabilia Banners, 1913-1937., Contains 16 historic banners used in parades and union halls. The banners are from Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (ACWA), Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers of America (ACTWU), and other unions and locals.
- 6200 P: UNITE HERE Photographs, 1962-2002., Contains photographs from UNITE, HERE, and UNITE HERE locals, conventions, and organizing drives.
- 6200 PUBS: UNITE HERE Publications, 2004-2008., Contains annual reports, constitutions, pension booklets, training booklets, and other informational material published by the union for its members.
- 6200/001: UNITE HERE Local 169 Files, 1938-2007., Contains local union material regarding New School University security officers.
- 6200/002: UNITE HERE Legal Department ACTWU Files, 1969-1995., Contains mostly documents pertaining to the merger of Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (ACWA) and Textile Workers Union of America (TWUA) into Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) in 1976. Also includes several ACWA and ACTWU national agreements.
- 6200/003: UNITE HERE Operations Department Files, 1989-2001., Contains convention material, reports, and organizing materials.
- 6200/004: UNITE HERE Sidney Hillman Foundation Awards, 2007-2008., Contains the awards presentation programs and other material for the 2007 and 2008 awards for socially-responsible journalism.
- 6200/005: UNITE HERE Local 23-25 Files, 1997-2008., Contains.
- 6200/005 MB: UNITE HERE Local 23-25 Memorabilia, 2004-2010., Contains awards given to May Chen, samples of clothing bearing the UNITE HERE logo for members, and other UNITE HERE union memorabilia.
- 6200/005 P: UNITE HERE Local 23-25 Photographs, 1971., Contains 11 photographs and 22 35mm slides, mostly unlabeled.
- 6200/006: UNITE HERE New Engalnd Joint Board Records, 1999-2008., Contains Joint Board records concerning negotiations with companies in the New England region.